Ranvijay Sachan

Career Highlights:

Total Exp: 8+ years

Having very good experience in developing applications from scratch(end to end). Building microservice services using python, django/flask, apache2, nginx, docker and kubernetes. Maintaining and Optimizing back end code for scalability and better Performance, Following Test Driven Development Architecture.

PERSONAL INFO

Father: Birendra K. Sachan **Mother**: Arunima Sachan

DOB: 05-06-1986 **PAN**: FVYPS2996K

EXPERIENCE (8+ years)

Aricent technologies, Gurgaon - *Technical Lead* (Oct 2017- Current)

Zymr System, Pune - *Sr. Software Engineer (***August 2016 - Sep-2017**)

Incredible Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai - SDE-1 (July 2015 - Jul 2016)

SRM Techsol. Pvt. Ltd, Lucknow - Software Engineer

(Aug 2011 - June 2015)

HONOR & AWARDS

- Employee of month Award in 2014
- CEO Appreciation award in 2016
- Team Excellence Award in 2017

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Application(MCA)
From Integral University, Lucknow - with 84%.

Address: Gurgaon, Haryana, India Email: sachan.ranvijay@gmail.com Mo: +91- 9987391275, 9319741275 Linkedin GitHub StackOverflow Website

SKILLS

Languages: **Python**, JavaScript, Html, Sql, shellScript, Java(Basic)

OS: Ubuntu, windows, Mac

Web Server: Apache2, Nginx, wisgi, asgi

Frameworks: Django, Django-Rest, Scrapy, ScrapyD, flask, ORM, whoosh, solar, pandas, RabbitMq, celery, redis, JWT, oauth2, AzureAd, Docker, React kubernetes, microservices etc..

Integration: **AWS**(bucket, SES, bolo, s3), Gupshup, Zoho, **salesforce**, twitter Api's, Logging(loggly), elasticsearch-dsl

DB: Mysql, **postgres**, sqlLite, Elastic, Whoosh, Hdf5, **mongoDB** etc.

Tools/OS: Pycharm,**GIT**, **Jenkins**(CI/CD), JIRA, Postman, Jmeter, **Swagger** etc...

Security Tools:

Nmap, **Nessus**, **Qark**, Sonarqube, **Openscap**, Dagda, Blackduck, Burpsuite etc..

Projects:

- Avert (Automated Vulnerability Ecosystem Resistance tactics)
- Design Hub
- Credr
- Cartwire
- Salesify
- Adobe TV
- CardioVIP

Languages

- English
- Hindi